# PETER WRATKOWSKI

Lakeville, MN 55044

Phone: (952) 484–0197 | Email: pwratkowski@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/peter-wratkowski | GitHub: https://github.com/peterwra Portfolio: https://peterwra.github.io/bio/

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

Application Systems Analyst with 15 years of extensive experience working with waterfall methodology. MERN full stack developer with experience in C# and Java. Received Scrum Master certificate in February 2018 to further project management and agile methodology experience.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

SQL, MongoDB, Java, C#, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Foxpro, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, VisualCron job scheduling software

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Sr Application Systems Analyst DCM Services, LLC

July 2012 - Present Minneapolis, MN

Work with Project Manager to coordinate new client on-boarding. Provide support for debt collection software system used by account representatives. Ensure client files are coded properly for transfer and processing.

- Took the initiative to research various job scheduling software systems and implemented VisualCron that manages
  over a thousand programs which transfer files and generate reports for internal and external clients resulting in
  hundreds of saved hours.
- Create programs in Foxpro and C# to automate reports from various data sources such as MS SQL, Cache database, Excel and flat files providing insight into trends which Operations uses to determine account workflow.
- Provide clarification and detailed requirements to the EDI team for business procedure documentation updates.
- Successfully ensure account flow and processes are in compliance with debt collection and health insurance laws such as FDCPA and HIPAA.
- Converted an unreliable and disjointed auto mailer system with a C# program to a new integrated program that processes database records and generates hundreds of daily emails with more efficiency and reliability.

# **Application Systems Analyst DCM Services, LLC**

May 2006 - July 2012 Minneapolis, MN

Provided support for the FACS debt collection software system. Analyzed client on-boarding documents and provided feedback to internal team members. Loaded client files into the database and review for errors.

- Effectively coordinate with client auditing team providing detailed reports to external auditors providing the necessary information to confirm that DCM is in compliance with client requirements.
- Analyzed vendor and client requirements and established data exchange and processing interfaces providing a streamlined approach to exchanging data and automating file exchanges.
- Facilitated migration between test and production database instances and verified testing protocols and use cases were documented before migration providing an audit trail during client inspection periods.

#### **EXPERIENCE Continued**

# Support Analyst HighJump Software

January 2004 - May 2006 Minneapolis, MN

Provided support for proprietary warehouse management software developed by HighJump Software. Fixed defects in customer applications. Coordinated with project teams to ensure go-live deadlines were met. Helped train customers with software.

- Effectively collaborated with the product development team to analyze and fix a loop in our software program that customers were experiencing. This was causing application timeouts on the warehouse scanners and leaving inventory stuck on forklifts and bin locations.
- Successfully coordinated with internal and external customers during go-live and upgrades ensuring testing scenarios were documented and results logged.
- Proficiently logged and maintained a list of defects in the Clientele issue tracking system. Successfully resolved over 2,000 issues with the various software applications used by customers.

## **PROJECTS**

# Parkify | https://github.com/peterwra/parkify | https://parkify-project3.herokuapp.com

- Created a park review website for families to identify the best and closest parks.
- Role: Back-End Developer
- Technologies used: MongoDB, React.js, Passport.js with Bcrypt encryption, Express.js, Node.js

## Word Guess | https://github.com/peterwra/Word-Guess-Game | https://peterwra.github.io/Word-Guess-Game/

- This is an app for One-hit wonders word guessers for solo artists and bands.
- Role: Front and Back End Developer
- Technologies used: jQuery, Bootstrap, Javascript

# National Parks Trivia | https://github.com/peterwra/TriviaGame | https://peterwra.github.io/TriviaGame/

- This is a trivia app with a list of 10 questions to test your knowledge of the national parks.
- Role: Front and Back End Developer
- Technologies used: CSS, ¡Query, Javascript timing events

# **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

# Web Development | Coding Certificate: University of Minnesota, St. Paul MN

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Scrum Master Certification: Scrum Alliance, Minneapolis MN

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science: St. Cloud State University, St. Cloud MN

Graduated in Honors Program. ACM member.